<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data_mapper on MetaBates.com</title>
    <link>/tags/data_mapper/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data_mapper on MetaBates.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Mark Bates.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/tags/data_mapper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 0.8.3</title>
      <link>/2009/01/18/release-083/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</author>
      <guid>/2009/01/18/release-083/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the cold and snowy New England winter this year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to devote quite a bit of time to getting Mack to run on Ruby 1.9, so with that said, here&amp;rsquo;s the 0.8.3 release of Mack, featuring&amp;hellip; TADA&amp;hellip; Ruby 1.9!! Of course there are a few other features and improvements in this release. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick run down:
&lt;h3&gt;Ruby 1.9&lt;/h3&gt;
The big one. Mack runs very well on Ruby 1.9, unfortunately I can&amp;rsquo;t say the same thing about some other frameworks. I&amp;rsquo;ve had some run ins with DataMapper on 1.9, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure those will be ironed out shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I announced I was working on getting Ruby 1.9 support for all my gems and libraries. I started out with Configatron, then upgraded Cachetastic and Genosaurus. Now Mack is 1.9 compatible. When I made the announcement the guys at RailsEnvy picked up on it and said that I made a call to arms to the community to pick up 1.9 support. Now granted, I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually say those words, but I think the intent was there, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to now officially say those words. This is a &amp;lsquo;call to arms&amp;rsquo; to the Ruby community to upgrade their gems, plugins, libraries, frameworks, etc&amp;hellip; to work on Ruby 1.9. I&amp;rsquo;ve done it, and I can tell you, it&amp;rsquo;s not that tough. Just use multiruby, and you&amp;rsquo;re off and running.
&lt;h3&gt;ActiveSupport In, Facets Out&lt;/h3&gt;
What with the world getting smaller these days, well, at least the world of Ruby web frameworks. A lot of great work is going into refactoring ActiveSupport and making it faster, better, and smaller. Because of that and the fact that every time a new release of Facets comes out it breaks a whole lot of stuff, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to use ActiveSupport as the basis of the mack-facets gem. So basically mack-facets is just ActiveSupport with a few more enhancements.
&lt;h3&gt;JavaScript Effects&lt;/h3&gt;
Thanks to the tireless efforts of Gerardo Pis-Lopez, mack-javascript, has been upgraded to add helpers methods for effects for both Prototype/Scriptaculous and jQuery. Thank you to Gerardo for the much needed upgraded to mack-javascript.
&lt;h3&gt;Upgrades&lt;/h3&gt;
Mack has been upgraded to use Rack 0.9.1, DataMapper 0.9.9, and a few other smaller gems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changelog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#243 - Upgraded to Rack 0.9.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#242 - Upgraded to DataMapper 0.9.9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#241 - Removed dependency on Facets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#239 - Add do_sqlite3 to gems.rb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#166 - Effects for mack-javascript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#133 - Added Form Builders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#22 - Ruby 1.9 Support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gem: rack 0.9.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gem: rspec 1.1.12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gem: configatron 2.2.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gem: cachetastic 2.1.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gem: data_mapper 0.9.9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gem: addressable 2.0.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gem: extlib 0.9.9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>