<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apn on MetaBates.com</title>
    <link>/tags/apn/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apn on MetaBates.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Mark Bates.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/tags/apn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>APN on Rails has a new Home.</title>
      <link>/2010/03/10/apn-on-rails-has-a-new-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</author>
      <guid>/2010/03/10/apn-on-rails-has-a-new-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quite often I get asked why don&amp;rsquo;t I blog more? Why don&amp;rsquo;t I tweet more? Why don&amp;rsquo;t I &lt;em&gt;fill in the blank&lt;/em&gt; more. The answer is I&amp;rsquo;m a busy man. I&amp;rsquo;m the CTO for a pre-funding startup, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shortbord.com/invites/ZAZLBQH5FA&#34;&gt;www.shortbord.com&lt;/a&gt;, the father of two adorable little boys, the lead singer of a Boston-based band, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myspace.com/colawarvets&#34;&gt;www.myspace.com/colawarvets&lt;/a&gt;, and that&amp;rsquo;s just the big stuff! I have to prioritize what I can spend my time on, and unfortunately some of my open source projects are the first to get the ax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do the open source projects always seem to get the ax? Well, let me start by saying that they don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; get the ax, but they certainly jump to the top of the list. There are certain libraries I&amp;rsquo;ve written, &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/markbates/cachetastic&#34;&gt;cachetastic&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/markbates/configatron&#34;&gt;configatron&lt;/a&gt;, are the two most prominent that I use day in and day out. They will always get the love the deserve. Then there are projects like APN on Rails. I wrote it because I had an iPhone app (no longer available) that I wanted notifications for, and there was nothing else available for Ruby to do the job. The plugin took off like crazy and I was overwhelmed with patches, questions, bugs, etc&amp;hellip; That was great, and I was happy to help, for a time, but alas, I haven&amp;rsquo;t written an iPhone app for ages, and I just don&amp;rsquo;t have time to maintain a plugin that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A while ago I realized that the best thing for APN on Rails, myself, and for the community was to find someone to take over the project so that it got the love it deserved. I put out the call and the good folks over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prx.org/&#34;&gt;PRX&lt;/a&gt; (Public Radio Exchange) answered the call. The folks at PRX have written some great iPhone apps, including the very popular &amp;laquo;This American Life&amp;raquo; app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that the new official home for APN on Rails is now at: &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/PRX/apn_on_rails&#34;&gt;http://github.com/PRX/apn_on_rails&lt;/a&gt;. I ask that you continue to show the same support to PRX that you have shown to me over the life of this plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, thank you to everyone, and thank you to Rebecca Nesson and the folks over at PRX for picking up the project and giving it renewed life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APN on Rails Needs a Home</title>
      <link>/2009/12/21/apn-on-rails-needs-a-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</author>
      <guid>/2009/12/21/apn-on-rails-needs-a-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there everyone, recently I have been getting a lot of requests for bug fixes and new features for the APN on Rails gem that I wrote. While I appreciate that the gem is getting a lot of use and helping a lot of people out, I, unfortunately, no longer have the time to maintain the gem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent changes in my career have meant that I have moved away from doing a lot o iPhone development, and because of that I no longer have the time, nor the desire, to keep maintaining a gem I&amp;rsquo;m no longer using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, because of that, I would to find a new home for the APN on Rails gem so that it gets the love and attention it so desires. Are there any takers out there? Is someone willing to take on the ownership of this, apparently, very useful gem? If you are willing to take it on, please let me know and we can workout the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who has said good things about the gem, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad that it has helped people get to using push notifications quicker, hopefully, one of you can take this project and run with it. Thanks again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APN on Rails 0.3.0 Released</title>
      <link>/2009/07/31/apn-on-rails-0-3-0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</author>
      <guid>/2009/07/31/apn-on-rails-0-3-0-released/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The latest version of Apple Push Notifications on Rails (APN on Rails) has been released. This release brings a few bug fixes, a new migration, and Feedback processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing/upgrading is easy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo gem install apn_on_rails
$ ruby script/generate apn_migrations
$ rake db:migrate
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to always run the migrations generator after each update to get the latest database schema needed for the the gem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use the new Feedback integration you have to first make sure that you update the new &lt;code&gt;last_registered_at&lt;/code&gt; column when your iPhone application calls home. This column is checked against the timestamp Apple returns with the device token. If the &lt;code&gt;last_registered_at&lt;/code&gt; is older than Apple&amp;rsquo;s date then the device is deleted, otherwise the Feedback is ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get and process the list of devices from Apple&amp;rsquo;s Feedback service just run the following Rake task:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ rake apn:feedback:process&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Push Notifications on Rails</title>
      <link>/2009/07/24/apple-push-notifications-on-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</author>
      <guid>/2009/07/24/apple-push-notifications-on-rails/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other night I submitted a new iPhone application to the Apple Store. The app, which I&amp;rsquo;ll speak about when, and if it gets approved, uses the new Apple Push Notification service available in iPhone OS 3.0. On the server side I have a Rails application that I am using to send the notifications to Apple. The problem I ran into was how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the APN on Rails gem. While searching I found one plugin for Rails that mostly worked for me, Sam Soffes&amp;rsquo; apple_push_notification plugin. It was a great place to start, but I found that there were things that didn&amp;rsquo;t suite me. For starters, not having any tests is always a big turn off for me when it comes to any code. I also didn&amp;rsquo;t like that you didn&amp;rsquo;t need to save a notification in order to send it. That means you don&amp;rsquo;t have a record of what was sent and when. I also wanted to have devices stored separately from the notification. Finally, I wanted to be able to easily configure the plugin. Sam&amp;rsquo;s was using constants that would need to be changed when it hit production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, with all that said and done I took Sam&amp;rsquo;s great work, ripped it apart, and put it back together again, this time in gem form instead of a plugin, and here it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few migrations, a few models, and a few Rake tasks, but here is the basic idea of how it works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;http://gist.github.com/154516.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a better understanding of exactly how it works, and what it does, I highly recommend reading the &lt;a href=&#34;http://apnonrails.metabates.com/&#34;&gt;RDOC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few things I still would like to add, for example, a controller to do CRUD for devices so iPhones can register with the Rails app. I&amp;rsquo;d also like to add a task that talks to Apple and finds out which devices are no longer accepting messages so they can be removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to contribute, please feel free and for the project on GitHub:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/markbates/apn_on_rails/tree&#34;&gt;http://github.com/markbates/apn_on_rails/tree&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, a special thanks to Fabien Penso and Sam Soffes for their initial work on this project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>