<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Distribunaut on MetaBates.com</title>
    <link>/tags/distribunaut/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Distribunaut on MetaBates.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Mark Bates.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/distribunaut/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Programming with Ruby Book Update</title>
      <link>/2009/05/22/distributed-programming-with-ruby-book-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</author>
      <guid>/2009/05/22/distributed-programming-with-ruby-book-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there folks, I know it&amp;rsquo;s been awhile, so I thought I would give you all a very quick update as to how the book is going. It&amp;rsquo;s going really well. I&amp;rsquo;m about 100 pages into it, and it&amp;rsquo;s shaping up very nicely. Addison-Wesley is preparing to put it into their &amp;ldquo;Rough Cuts&amp;rdquo; program so you can all get your dirty little hands on what I&amp;rsquo;ve written so far as early as a few weeks from now, or so I&amp;rsquo;m told.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I don&amp;rsquo;t want to give too much away about the contents, everybody loves a good surprise, let me say that part one of the book will be the most comprehensive guide to DRb and Rinda that you&amp;rsquo;ll find anywhere. Including the source code!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working hard on part two of the book which focuses on third party tools, frameworks, and libraries. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a fun part of the book to write as there are a great deal of choices out there, including my own Distribunaut. (PS. I released a new version of it on GitHub a week or so ago.) Writing about different libraries is quite fun as I get to really delve into the source code and see the good and bad ways people like to write code. Plus some of the libraries have really great features, or really turn things on their head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the book is available as a &amp;ldquo;Rough Cut&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;ll certainly keep you all informed. In the mean time keep watching this space and have a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distribunaut</title>
      <link>/2009/04/05/distribunaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</author>
      <guid>/2009/04/05/distribunaut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there everyone, it certainly has been awhile, a month by my count. I have been diligently working on a book for Addison-Wesley called, &amp;ldquo;Distributed Programming with Ruby&amp;rdquo;, so having the time to blog went from a luxury to almost non-existent. But here&amp;rsquo;s another little post to keep your RSS feeds happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started working on porting the mack-distributed package to the non-Mack world. This new project, and I use the term new loosely for the time being, is tentatively called Distribunaut. The project on GitHub can be found here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/markbates/distribunaut/tree/master&#34;&gt;http://github.com/markbates/distribunaut/tree/master&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty rough right now. I&amp;rsquo;ve ported over the distributed objects section of mack-distributed, but not the views and routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can install the gem like such:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ gem sources -a &lt;a href=&#34;http://gems.github.com&#34;&gt;http://gems.github.com&lt;/a&gt;
$ sudo gem install markbates-distribunaut&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use Distribunaut we first need to start a Rinda::RingServer. Distribunaut comes with a binary to help make this easier:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ distribunaut_ring_server start&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we&amp;rsquo;ve done that we can create an object we would like to share:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;http://gist.github.com/90620.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we run that we can access it like such:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;http://gist.github.com/90621.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That would result in the following being printed out by our &amp;lsquo;client&amp;rsquo; code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;http://gist.github.com/90622.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our &amp;lsquo;server&amp;rsquo; side we would see something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;http://gist.github.com/90623.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is, clearly, a very simple example, but it shows you how easy it is to use Distribunaut. We haven&amp;rsquo;t done any real configuration, and things just magically work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next couple of months I&amp;rsquo;ll be extending and rebuilding this library to make it even more powerful and easy to use. I&amp;rsquo;m going to add fault tolerance, selection algorithms, and whole lot more. The API you see in these examples will most likely remain unchanged, but I&amp;rsquo;m planning on pretty big under the cover changes.There will be a very in-depth look into all of this in the book, obviously. (Shameless plug, I know.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anybody out there wants to contribute to this project, I&amp;rsquo;d love the help. Any sort of feedback is welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>