<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jekyll on MetaBates.com</title>
    <link>/tags/jekyll/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jekyll on MetaBates.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Mark Bates.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 16:20:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/jekyll/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Building With Hugo</title>
      <link>/2016/06/09/now-building-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 16:20:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</author>
      <guid>/2016/06/09/now-building-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently a good friend of mine, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/spf13&#34;&gt;Steve Francia&lt;/a&gt;, released a new version of his static site generator, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/meta/release-notes/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. So I thought I would give it a spin to see if it&amp;rsquo;s any better than my old platform, &lt;a href=&#34;/2012/04/04/now-blogging-with-jekyll/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big reason that I was interested in Hugo, wasn&amp;rsquo;t just because I&amp;rsquo;m friends with Steve, but rather speed. Jekyll had always been easy to use, but it was pretty slow. Like really slow. I also had the occasional issue with it not properly building after I would save a file. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that Jekyll was bad, but there was definitely room for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had tried previously to switch over to Hugo, but there wasn&amp;rsquo;t a good way to import from Jekyll and I had a) no intentions of manually converting all my previous posts and b) losing all of that content and starting over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent some time with Steve a few weeks ago, and he told me that the latest version of Hugo had built-in support for importing Jekyll, and that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to rely on hacking third party scripts to get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After running the importer all of my posts were there, and they only needed a wee bit of tweaking to make them look good with Hugo. Then I was off trying to find a good theme for the site, preferably something similar to what I had. That was easy enough, a few tweaks to a &amp;ldquo;bootstrap&amp;rdquo; theme and I was set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I&amp;rsquo;ve been happy with Hugo, now that I have it set up. I just hit save and Hugo rebuilt my entire site in &lt;code&gt;234ms&lt;/code&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s pretty darn fast! Especially compared with the speeds I was getting with Jekyll. Oh, and did I mention that it also reloaded the site in my browser for me so I can see it getting updated everytime I hit save? Yeah, pretty nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, I&amp;rsquo;m sold on Hugo. Does that mean I will blog more? Who knows? I do know that it certainly couldn&amp;rsquo;t hurt. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Blogging with Jekyll</title>
      <link>/2012/04/04/now-blogging-with-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</author>
      <guid>/2012/04/04/now-blogging-with-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may or may not have noticed there&amp;rsquo;s a new blog in town! That&amp;rsquo;s right, I&amp;rsquo;ve ditched the zero, WordPress, and got with the hero, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. And I have to say, it sure feels good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WordPress worked well for me for years, but I have to say that I never enjoyed the process of writing a technical blog in a browser. I hated the lack of tools that my editor has at it&amp;rsquo;s disposal. It was too slow to do previews with. And all together it just always felt a bit &amp;ldquo;hacky&amp;rdquo;, and not in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll let&amp;rsquo;s me write my blog entries in my favorite local text editor. I can preview my blog, locally, which is great if you want to make a sweeping change to the whole thing. When I&amp;rsquo;m done writing I can do a &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt; and the site now has all the new content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that I haven&amp;rsquo;t been that great over the last few months at keeping this blog up to date. Part of that was due to writing a new book, &lt;a href=&#34;http://books.markbates.com&#34;&gt;Programming in CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt;, and the other because I just didn&amp;rsquo;t like writing in WordPress. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that now that I&amp;rsquo;ve got a bit more of a &amp;ldquo;hacker&amp;rdquo; friendly way of blogging, that I get back into the habit of blogging more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s to the hopes of happy blogging!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>