<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sass on MetaBates.com</title>
    <link>/tags/sass/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sass on MetaBates.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Mark Bates.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/tags/sass/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you.</title>
      <link>/2009/03/04/thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</author>
      <guid>/2009/03/04/thank-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is with a sad and heavy heart that this evening I announce that I will no longer be developing the Mack Framework. The project, started a year ago, and has been source of great pride, joy, and at times frustation. Of all the projects I have ever worked on, this one was definitely closest to my heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decision to stop working on Mack was something I did not take lightly. If I had my druthers, and plenty of free time and a source of funding, I most certainly would continue on working on it. However, reality has a different way of plenty out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started developing Mack the company I was working for at the time was frustrated with the pains and shortcomings of Rails. It was the right platform for the company when we started, however, two years in a start up is a life time and the company took many twists and turns, that lead us to the path of seeking an alternative platform to Rails. At the time Merb was not a serious contender, and there was little else out there that was looking to satisfy the needs we had. Enter Mack. I spent nearly 10 months developing Mack for that company. We rolled out several Mack applications. It worked really well for what we wanted it to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, however, reality came into play. The company was forced to lay off nearly 50% of its staff, and I was one of them. I quickly took a position as the Director of Engineering for another startup in Boston. This shop, too, is a Rails shop. The difference between the two companies is that for the company I work for now Rails is the right solution. This means that I am spending my days working with Rails, and not developing Mack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At night and on the weekends I like to spend time with my wife and my son. I play in a band, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thebluewires.com&#34;&gt;www.thebluewires.com&lt;/a&gt;, and I am working on a book for Addison-Wesley entitled, &amp;laquo;Distributed Programming with Ruby&amp;raquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m a busy man, and Mack is a big project. You can&amp;rsquo;t successfully write a web framework part time. Especially when that part time is really more like part-part time. You need to be able to put dedicated full time resources onto a project of that scale, and I just don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would I love to see the project continue? Certainly. If there is someone out there who wants to take it on, please let me know. I would love to see it grow. There is so much I wanted to do with it. So many great ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, for the good news, I am planning to port a bunch of the Mack functionality over to the Rails 3 platform. The obvious one being the mack-distributed package which is a key differentiator between Mack and the other Ruby frameworks. Another package I think worthy of migration is mack-notifier, which provides, in my opinion, a really nice clean API for doing notifications, whether they be email, Jabber, SMS, etc&amp;hellip; I also really like the mack-data_factory package. It provides an ORM agnostic way to do great data factories for testing. Finally there are some routing improvements that I think Rails could really benefit from, as well as a few other bits and bobs here and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish to thank everyone who has supported this project over the year. A few key people I think that deserve a special call out are: Darsono Sutedja (the second biggest contributed to Mack), Gerardo Pis-Lopez (the third biggest contributor), and Greg Arsenault (my previous boss who fought for me to develop Mack). If there was such a thing as the Mack Core Team, those guys would be it. I would also like to thank people like Peter Cooper, Gregg Pollack, Adam French, Dan Kubb, and everyone else who either opened a Lighthouse ticket, submitted a patch, wrote a blog entry about Mack, or who was just there for support and guidance over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to keep www.mackframework.com around as a forum for my other projects, such as Cachetastic and Configatron, and the other projects I have brewing. Expect some cool new projects out of me in 2009, include some iPhone projects that I&amp;rsquo;m excited about undertaking. I will be releasing the last version of Mack by the end of the month. It will essentially be a few bug fixes, an upgrade of DataMapper, and Sass support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarize, thank you everyone. I appreciate your support and I look forward to contributing to the community in new and exciting ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>