<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Map Reduce on MetaBates.com</title>
    <link>/tags/map-reduce/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Map Reduce on MetaBates.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Mark Bates.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/map-reduce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost There... Book Wise.</title>
      <link>/2009/07/27/almost-there-book-wise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</author>
      <guid>/2009/07/27/almost-there-book-wise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m now entering the home stretch of writing the Distributed Programming with Ruby book. I&amp;rsquo;m just a few weeks away, well, technically I&amp;rsquo;m hours away from finishing the last chapter (Delayed Job) in the official table of contents, however, I&amp;rsquo;m going to add another chapter and a half. Why? Mostly because I&amp;rsquo;m a glutton for punishment. That and I want to deliver the best book possible. The extra chapter and a half, not featured in the table of contents below, will be on MapReduce technologies. It&amp;rsquo;s a really hot topic, and I think it will fit well in the book. What do you think?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;del datetime=&#34;2009-07-29T03:01:37+00:00&#34;&gt;Unfortunately, the &amp;ldquo;Rough Cuts&amp;rdquo; book on O&amp;rsquo;Reilly&amp;rsquo;s Safari site hasn&amp;rsquo;t been updated in nearly 3 months! I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why. I keep asking my editor to update it, but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t happened yet. I&amp;rsquo;m sure it will soon, especially since the first draft of the entire manuscript will be done in just a few weeks!&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Today they updated the &amp;ldquo;Rough Cuts&amp;rdquo; with nearly the latest revisions. It&amp;rsquo;s still missing the chapters on Delayed Job and BackgrounDRb, but it&amp;rsquo;s closer than it was yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, as a public service announcement to you, the readers, I thought I would the table of contents as it stands right now, so you have a better idea of what the book is going to be about. So here it goes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;http://gist.github.com/156861.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think? Does it look good? Is this something you&amp;rsquo;d buy? Let me know. This is your chance to have an influence on a book. If you think something is missing or should be laid out differently, please let me know, it might just make it into the final product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, enough delaying here, let me get back to writing so I can finish up the Delayed Job chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>