<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linelytics on MetaBates.com</title>
    <link>/tags/linelytics/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linelytics on MetaBates.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Mark Bates.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/tags/linelytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducting LineLytics.com</title>
      <link>/2013/06/02/introducting-linelyticscom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mark&#43;blog@markbates.com (Mark Bates)</author>
      <guid>/2013/06/02/introducting-linelyticscom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.linelytics.com/assets/screenshots/dashboard.png&#34; class=&#34;img-right&#34; style=&#34;width: 400px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am announcing the release of a new SaaS application I&amp;rsquo;ve written, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linelytics.com?from=metabates.com&#34;&gt;LineLytics.com&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m very excited about this application, and if you are a &lt;a href=&#34;http://stripe.com&#34;&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt; user, then you should be too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linelytics.com?from=metabates.com&#34;&gt;LineLytics.com&lt;/a&gt;? First, let me give you a little background on how the application came to be. At the beginning of the year I announced my weekly screen cast site, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metacasts.tv&#34;&gt;MetaCasts.tv&lt;/a&gt;. The site has a monthly subscription of $9, or a yearly subscription of $90. If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to subscribe you can also buy individual videos, usually around $6 each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it came time to implement the purchasing/subscribing functionality in MetaCasts I looked at all the different payment processors on the market. I&amp;rsquo;ve used several different ones in the past, and was never satisfied with them. Either they charged too much (even if you weren&amp;rsquo;t making any money) or they were difficult to implement. Usually it was both. Then I found &lt;a href=&#34;http://stripe.com&#34;&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://stripe.com&#34;&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt; was a revelation. It was both sanely priced (2.9% + $.30) &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; easy to implement. I was in love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.linelytics.com/assets/screenshots/sales.png&#34; class=&#34;img-left&#34; style=&#34;width: 400px&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After using &lt;a href=&#34;http://stripe.com&#34;&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt; for several months to power MetaCasts, I found a chink in their armor. I had no idea where my revenue was coming from. Which of my products were selling the best? Which coupons were proving effective? What was my subscriber churn? I needed this information, and more. I needed to be able to analyze my revenue and make decisions based on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is where &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linelytics.com?from=metabates.com&#34;&gt;LineLytics.com&lt;/a&gt;. Knowing that &lt;a href=&#34;http://stripe.com&#34;&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt; has an amazing API I was able to build an application that provided to me, in real-time mind you, all sorts of great information about my sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linelytics.com?from=metabates.com&#34;&gt;LineLytics.com&lt;/a&gt; last couple of months while I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing it, and I can tell you my mind has been blown at some of the information I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in my data. Information that is just not readily apparent in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://stripe.com&#34;&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt; platform today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could go into specifics about the technologies I&amp;rsquo;m using, but I won&amp;rsquo;t, this isn&amp;rsquo;t that sort of post. Instead I just want to say that if you too are a &lt;a href=&#34;http://stripe.com&#34;&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt; customer, than you owe it to yourself to sign up for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linelytics.com?from=metabates.com&#34;&gt;LineLytics.com&lt;/a&gt; your business better than you&amp;rsquo;ve ever been able to before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to seeing how people use the application, and I&amp;rsquo;m open to any suggestions you might have on reports that you&amp;rsquo;d like to see, I know I have a lot of great ideas that I still want to implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#39;text-align: center&#39;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.linelytics.com?from=metabates.com&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39; class=&#39;btn btn-large btn-primary&#39;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Check out LineLytics.com&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>